Hudson Valley GREEN Collection
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Hudson Valley GREEN Collection
1981 - 2002
NPKMC-222-181
20.67 linear feet
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Hudson Valley GREEN
The Hudson Valley GREEN (Grass Roots Energy & Environmental Network) Collection documents the development of the environmental group and their constant vigilance in protecting the environment in the Hudson River Valley Area. This collection includes printed material, environmental magazines and newspapers, Hudson Valley GREEN Times, background material, business files, slides and film, as well as a variety of other documents and reports funded by the New York State Government and other Federal organizations. Also included in the collection are files dealing with specific topics such as Indian Point, James Bay, 765 Power Line Controversy, Con Edison v. Mid Hudson Nuclear Opponents and the Town of Red Hook as well as variety of other topics.
Related Collections
Collection Overview
The Hudson Valley GREEN Collection documents the growth and development of Hudson Valley GREEN. The collection consists of subject files, printed material, government, state, and privately funded reports and documents, background materials, business files and audio-visual arrangements.
Hudson Valley GREEN donated the Hudson Valley GREEN Collection to the Marist College Library in 2003.
Historical Note
Hudson Valley GREEN (Grass Roots Energy & Environmental Network) was formed in January 1981 with the merger of Mid-Hudson Nuclear Opponents, Citizens for Safe Power Transmissions and Concerned Citizens for Safe Energy. GREEN is a non-profit membership supported organization interested in safe energy, environmental conservation, and sustainable development of local communities. Their goal is to help inform and increase public participation in the debate and policy making process involved with environmental and development issues facing communities in the Hudson Valley. Hudson Valley GREEN publishes a quarterly newspaper the Hudson Valley GREEN Times. The GREEN Times is the main project of the organization. The newspaper carries news of GREEN and other regional environmental and community groups, articles on local environmental issues, editorials, guides to regional resources, and sustainable businesses and a calendar of events. The Hudson Valley GREEN Times is free and distributed throughout Ulster and Dutchess counties in New York State.
Restrictions to Access
There are no restrictions on this collection
Arrangement of the Collection
These records are organized into six series: 1) Subject files, has sixteen subseries, 2) Printed Material, has four subseries, 3) Government, State, and Privately Funded Reports, has nine subseries, 4) Background Materials and Business Files, has five subseries, 5) Audio-Visual Arrangement, has two subseries, 6) Archives Files
Series are arranged alphabetically and by subject
- 1. Subject Files, 1; 11 linear feet Boxes: 1 - 32 Folders: 1 - 318
  Series contains superies seperated on the topics of Environmental Importance and concern researched by Hudson Valley GREEN.
  Alphabetically and by Subject
  - Subseries 1.: 765 Power Line, 1981 - 2002; 1.1; 1 linear feet Boxes: 1 - 3 Folders: 1 - 17
    Series contains background documents, correspondence, newspaper clippings, reports and studies related to the 765 Power Line
    - 765 General Information (Folder 1, Box 1)
    - Correspondence (Folder 2, Box 1)
    - 765 KV Transmission kit (Folder 3, Box 1)
    - 765-Power line reports (Folder 4, Box 1)
    - 765 Electromagnetic Fields (Folder 5, Box 1)
    - 765-Newspaper clippings (Folder 6, Box 2)
    - 765-Magazine articles (Folder 7, Box 2)
    - Dutchess Anti-765 (Folder 8, Box 2)
    - Anti 765 Songs and Poems (Folder 9, Box 2)
    - 765 Related Newspapers (Folder 10, Box 2)
    - Public Service Commission Papers (Folder 11, Box 2)
    - 765 Testimony and Legal (Folder 12, Box 2)
    - Perceptions of Landowners about the effects of the UPA/CPA Power line on Human and Animal Health in West Central Minn. (Folder 13, Box 3)
    - University of Vermont: 765 Power Line Study (Folder 14, Box 3)
    - Residual Effects of Power Line Construction: A Rural Community Two Year Later (Folder 15, Box 3)
    - Biological Effects of High Strength Electric Fields on Small Laboratory Animals (Folder 16, Box 3)
    - 765 Health Issues (Folder 17, Box 3)
  - Subseries 1.2: Conservation, 1.2; 0.33 linear feet Box: 4 Folders: 18 - 20
    Series contains Simple ideas presented in pamphlets and hand outs describing conservation.
    - Conservation, General Information (Folder 18, Box 4)
    - Conservation, Wiz Kids 1-4 (Folder 19, Box 4)
    - Positive Solution (Folder 20, Box 4)
  - Subseries 1.3: Consolidated Edison of New York v. Mid Hudson Nuclear Opponents, Town of Red Hook, 1.3; 1.34 linear feet Boxes: 5 - 8 Folders: 21 - 47
    Series contains X, Y, and Z.
    Original Order/Alphabetical/Chronological/Subject
    - U.S. Law Week, Reference Case (Folder 21, Box 5)
    - Appellate Division, Reply Brief of Plaintiff-Appellant-Respondent, Consolidated Edison of New York (Folder 22, Box 5)
    - Court of Appeals, Brief of Intervenors-Defendants-Respondents, Mid-Hudson Nuclear Opponents Inc, Et Al., May 4, 1983 (Folder 23, Box 5)
    - Appellate Division, Brief of Plaintiff-Appellant-Respondent, 1978 (Folder 24, Box 5)
    - Court of Appeals, Brief of Plaintiff-Appellant, Consolidated Edison of New York, Inc., 1983 (Folder 25, Box 5)
    - Court of Appeals, Record on Appeal Con Ed v. Town of Red Hook &Mid Hudson Nuclear Opponents, 1983 (Folder 26, Box 5)
    - Court of Appeals, Notice of Motion, Affidavit and Brief in Opposition to Motion, Affirmation in Opposition to Motion (Folder 27, Box 5)
    - Court of Appeals, Brief of Defendants-Town of Red Hook, Brief of Plaintiff- Consolidated Edison (Folder 28, Box 5)
    - Supreme Court Filing, Summary Judgment, Appeals, Local Law Filing (Folder 29, Box 5)
    - Consolidated Edison / Red Hook Correspondence (Folder 30, Box 6)
    - Letters to Governor Cuomo concerning Con Edison (Folder 31, Box 6)
    - Public Service Commission, Con Ed Conservation Program 1986, Status Report 1985 (Folder 32, Box 6)
    - Con Ed / Red Hook, Public Service Commission Reports, 1983 (Folder 33, Box 6)
    - Reports Written in Response to Con Ed Power lines and Power Plants (Folder 34, Box 6)
    - Commission Reports, Information, and Speeches on Con Ed (Folder 35, Box 6)
    - Con Ed Power Plant Cancellation Information (Folder 36, Box 7)
    - Con Ed Survey (Folder 37, Box 7)
    - Landowners Affected by Con Ed (Folder 38, Box 7)
    - Mid Hudson at Rick Slide Script (Folder 39, Box 7)
    - Mid Hudson Nuclear Opponents, History and Minutes of Meetings (Folder 40, Box 7)
    - Con Ed Task Force Clippings (Folder 41, Box 8)
    - Nuclear Plant Clippings (Folder 42, Box 8)
    - Misc. Con Ed Newspaper Articles, no date (Folder 43, Box 8)
    - Con-Ed Clippings 1978-1979 (Folder 44, Box 8)
    - Con-Ed Clippings, 1980-1982 (Folder 45, Box 8)
    - Con Ed Clippings, 1983-1986 (Folder 46, Box 8)
    - Con Ed Clippings, 1986-1987 (Folder 47, Box 8)
  - Subseries 1.4: Energy / Solid Waste, 1.4; 0.33 linear feet Box: 9 Folders: 48 - 52
    Series contains general information on energy and solid waste.
    - Energy, General Pamphlets (Folder 48, Box 9)
    - Misc. Energy Literature (Folder 49, Box 9)
    - Solid Waste, General Information (Folder 50, Box 9)
    - Solid Waste Education Materials (Folder 51, Box 9)
    - Solid Waste, Newspaper Clippings (Folder 52, Box 9)
  - Subseries 1.5: Environmental Issues, 1.5; 2 linear feet Boxes: 10 - 15 Folders: 53 - 127
    Series contains Alphabetically listed issues that were major concerns of Hudson Valley GREEN.
    - Acid Rain, Information Pamphlets (Folder 53, Box 10)
    - Acid Rain, Media Articles (Folder 54, Box 10)
    - Ancient Forests (Folder 55, Box 10)
    - Article VIII of the Public Service Law (Folder 56, Box 10)
    - Bioregionalism (Folder 57, Box 10)
    - Boyce Thompson Institute for Plant Research (Folder 58, Box 10)
    - Clean Energy Campaign (Folder 59, Box 10)
    - Climate Change (Folder 60, Box 10)
    - Composting (Folder 61, Box 10)
    - Deregulation of Rad Waste (Folder 62, Box 11)
    - Desert Storm Information (Folder 63, Box 11)
    - Earth Resources, Satellite Data Application Series (Folder 64, Box 11)
    - Farms (Folder 65, Box 11)
    - Films on Environmental Issues (Folder 66, Box 11)
    - First National Labor Conference (Folder 67, Box 11)
    - Food Policy (Folder 68, Box 11)
    - GINNA (Folder 69, Box 11)
    - Global Action Plan (Folder 70, Box 11)
    - Global Warming (Folder 71, Box 11)
    - GM Foods (Folder 72, Box 11)
    - Green Parties (Folder 73, Box 11)
    - Ground Water (Folder 74, Box 11)
    - Ground Zero (Folder 75, Box 11)
    - Gypsy Moth (Folder 76, Box 11)
    - Household Hazardous Materials (Folder 77, Box 12)
    - How to Form a Green (Folder 78, Box 12)
    - How to Save Money on Your Water Bill (Folder 79, Box 12)
    - Incinerators (Folder 80, Box 12)
    - Impact of the Federal Budget on Dutchess County (Folder 81, Box 12)
    - Infant Nutrition in Third World Countries (Folder 82, Box 12)
    - Institute for Local Self Reliance, Facts to Act On (Folder 83, Box 12)
    - Integrated Pest Management Information (Folder 84, Box 12)
    - Lake Champlain Basin Environmental Conference (Folder 85, Box 12)
    - Land use, Eminent Domain (Folder 86, Box 12)
    - Land Use, General Information (Folder 87, Box 12)
    - Land Use, Correspondence (Folder 88, Box 12)
    - Lighthouses (Folder 89, Box 12)
    - Local Environmental Educational Resources (Folder 90, Box 12)
    - Low Level Electromagnetic Fields (Folder 91, Box 12)
    - Lyme Disease (Folder 92, Box 12)
    - Maps (Folder 93, Box 12)
    - Minewaska (Folder 94, Box 12)
    - Municipal Power (Folder 95, Box 12)
    - Nevada Test Site (Folder 96, Box 13)
    - Ozone (Folder 97, Box 13)
    - Pesticides (Folder 98, Box 13)
    - Phantom Taxes (Folder 99, Box 13)
    - Plants (Folder 100, Box 13)
    - Pollutants (Folder 101, Box 13)
    - Pollution in New York State (Folder 102, Box 13)
    - Power line 345, NYS Public Service Commission Testimony (Folder 103, Box 13)
    - Public Power (Folder 104, Box 13)
    - Radon Mining (Folder 105, Box 14)
    - Rainforest (Folder 106, Box 14)
    - Save the St. Lawrence River (Folder 107, Box 14)
    - School Materials on Environmental Education (Folder 108, Box 14)
    - Steam Electric Generating Facilities (Folder 109, Box 14)
    - SUNDAY (Folder 110, Box 14)
    - Texas Water Commission (Folder 111, Box 14)
    - The Turning Point (Folder 112, Box 14)
    - The Cornucopia Project (Folder 113, Box 14)
    - Toxic Dumpsites (Folder 114, Box 14)
    - Toxins (Folder 115, Box 14)
    - Transportation Spending and Economic Growth (Folder 116, Box 14)
    - Trident (Folder 117, Box 14)
    - Ulster County Hazardous Waste Management Program (Folder 118, Box 15)
    - Uranium Mining (Folder 119, Box 15)
    - Urban Sprawl (Folder 120, Box 15)
    - Waste Management (Folder 121, Box 15)
    - Water Crisis / Water Management (Folder 122, Box 15)
    - Water, Reports (Folder 123, Box 15)
    - Water, Information Pamphlets (Folder 124, Box 15)
    - Water Treatment Notes (Folder 125, Box 15)
    - Wilderness (Folder 126, Box 15)
    - WTO (Folder 127, Box 15)
  - Subseries 1.6: Environmental Organizations, 1.6; 1.67 linear feet Boxes: 16 - 20 Folders: 128 - 220
    Series contains alphabetically listed environmental organizations that Hudson Valley GREEN supported and/or had dealings with.
    - Bard College Center Community Focus (Folder 128, Box 16)
    - Black Hills Alliance (Folder 129, Box 16)
    - Campaign for Political Rights (Folder 130, Box 16)
    - Center for Health, Environment, and Justice (Folder 131, Box 16)
    - Citizens Against Airport Noise (Folder 132, Box 16)
    - Citizen/Labor Energy Coalition (Folder 133, Box 16)
    - Citizens Energy Project (Folder 134, Box 16)
    - Citizens Environmental Coalition (Folder 135, Box 16)
    - Citizens for the Hudson Valley (Folder 136, Box 16)
    - Citizens in Action (Folder 137, Box 16)
    - Citizens Utility Board, CUB (Folder 138, Box 16)
    - Clergy and Laity Concerned, CALC (Folder 139, Box 16)
    - Committee for Nuclear Responsibility (Folder 140, Box 16)
    - Consumer Federation of America (Folder 141, Box 16)
    - Cooperative Self Reliance Task Force (Folder 142, Box 16)
    - Cornell Waste Management Institute (Folder 143, Box 16)
    - Council on the Environment of New York City (Folder 144, Box 16)
    - Critical Mass (Folder 145, Box 16)
    - Dutchess County Environmental Management Council (Folder 146, Box 17)
    - Dutchess Land Conservancy (Folder 147, Box 17)
    - Eastern Federation (Folder 148, Box 17)
    - Educators for Social Responsibility (Folder 149, Box 17)
    - Energy Unlimited (Folder 150, Box 17)
    - Environmental Action Foundation (Folder 151, Box 17)
    - Environmental Advocates (Folder 152, Box 17)
    - Environmental Defense Fund (Folder 153, Box 17)
    - Environmental Planning Lobby (Folder 154, Box 17)
    - Environmental Policy Center (Folder 155, Box 17)
    - Environmental Policy Institute Publications (Folder 156, Box 17)
    - Environmental Support Center (Folder 157, Box 17)
    - Environmental Task Force (Folder 158, Box 17)
    - Environmental Task Force, Printed Material (Folder 159, Box 17)
    - Environmentalists for Full Employment (Folder 160, Box 17)
    - Federated Conservationists of Westchester County (Folder 161, Box 17)
    - Friends of the Earth (Folder 162, Box 17)
    - Fund for Renewable Energy and the Environment (Folder 163, Box 17)
    - Gandhi in Action (Folder 164, Box 17)
    - GREEN Party (Folder 165, Box 17)
    - Green Peace (Folder 166, Box 17)
    - Harlem Valley Transportation Association, HVTA (Folder 167, Box 18)
    - Hudson River Greenway, Correspondence (Folder 168, Box 18)
    - Hudson River Greenway, Information Packets (Folder 169, Box 18)
    - Hudson River Heritage (Folder 170, Box 18)
    - Hudson River Sloop, Clearwater Inc. (Folder 171, Box 18)
    - Hudson Valley Environmental Groups (Folder 172, Box 18)
    - Hy Ruchlis (Folder 173, Box 18)
    - Inform (Folder 174, Box 18)
    - Institute for Local Self Reliance (Folder 175, Box 18)
    - Komanoff (Folder 176, Box 18)
    - Labor Committee for Safe Energy and Full Employment (Folder 177, Box 18)
    - Manitoga (Folder 178, Box 18)
    - Mid-Hudson Environmental Network (Folder 179, Box 18)
    - Misc. national Groups (Folder 180, Box 18)
    - Misc. New York State Groups (Folder 181, Box 18)
    - Momentum (Folder 182, Box 18)
    - National Coalition Against the Misuse of Pesticides (Folder 183, Box 19)
    - National Committee for an Effective Congress (Folder 184, Box 19)
    - National Resource Defense Council (Folder 185, Box 19)
    - Nuclear Information and Resource Service (Folder 186, Box 19)
    - NY Farm Bureau (Folder 187, Box 19)
    - New York Land Institute (Folder 188, Box 19)
    - New York State Political Action Committee for the Environment (NYSPACE) (Folder 189, Box 19)
    - OMEGA Institute (Folder 190, Box 19)
    - Orange Environment (Folder 191, Box 19)
    - Over flights (Folder 192, Box 19)
    - PASNY (Folder 193, Box 19)
    - PASNY, Reforms (Folder 194, Box 19)
    - People’s Action for Clean Energy (Folder 195, Box 19)
    - Peoples Power Coalition, PPC (Folder 196, Box 19)
    - PPC Newsletter (Folder 197, Box 19)
    - Public Citizen (Folder 198, Box 19)
    - Public Utility Law Project, PULP (Folder 199, Box 19)
    - Rights for American Indians Now, RAIN (Folder 200, Box 19)
    - SANE (Folder 201, Box 20)
    - SHAD (Folder 202, Box 20)
    - Safe Energy Communications Council (Folder 203, Box 20)
    - Shore Walkers of New York (Folder 204, Box 20)
    - SHOW (Folder 205, Box 20)
    - Sierra Club (Folder 206, Box 20)
    - Small Farm Energy Project (Folder 207, Box 20)
    - Southern Poverty Law Center, SPLC (Folder 208, Box 20)
    - Solar Action Council (Folder 209, Box 20)
    - Solar Lobby (Folder 210, Box 20)
    - Taskforce Against Nuclear Energy (Folder 211, Box 20)
    - The Lakeshore Alliance (Folder 212, Box 20)
    - The non-profit Mailers Federation (Folder 213, Box 20)
    - Ulster County Environmental Federation (Folder 214, Box 20)
    - Union of Concerned Scientists (Folder 215, Box 20)
    - U.S. Forest Service (Folder 216, Box 20)
    - War Resisters League, WRL (Folder 217, Box 20)
    - Work on Waste, WOW (Folder 218, Box 20)
    - World Watch (Folder 219, Box 20)
    - Youth Conservation Corp. (Folder 220, Box 20)
  - Subseries 1.7: Hudsonia, James Bay, Long Island Sound Study, 1.7; 0.33 linear feet Box: 21 Folders: 221 - 227
    Series contains Reports and studies conducted on Hudsonia, James Bay and the Long Island Sound.
    - Hudsonia Habitat Analysis (Folder 221, Box 21)
    - James Bay Reports (Folder 222, Box 21)
    - James Bay Newsletter and Articles, 1990-1994 (Folder 223, Box 21)
    - James Bay information sheets (Folder 224, Box 21)
    - James Bay Pamphlets and News Releases (Folder 225, Box 21)
    - James Bay Correspondence, 1990-1994 (Folder 226, Box 21)
    - Long Island Sound Study (Folder 227, Box 21)
  - Subseries 1.8: Hudson River, 1.8; 0.33 linear feet Box: 22 Folders: 228 - 234
    Series contains Reports and analyses conducted on the Hudson River
    - Assessing the Impact of Development on Scenic Resources of the Hudson River (Folder 228, Box 22)
    - Hudson River Estuary (Folder 229, Box 22)
    - PCB’s(a) (Folder 230, Box 22)
    - PCB’s(b) (Folder 231, Box 22)
    - The Great Hudson River Revival (Folder 232, Box 22)
    - The Hudson River Trial (Folder 233, Box 22)
    - Rivers and Estuaries Center on the Hudson (Folder 234, Box 22)
  - Subseries 1.9: Iroquois Gas Transmission System, 1.9; 0.33 linear feet Box: 23 Folders: 235 - 244
    Series contains testimonies given to the Public Service Commission on a variety of dates concerning the gas transmission system.
    - Public Service Committee Session, August 10, 1988 (Folder 235, Box 23)
    - Public Service Committee Session, March 8, 1989 (Folder 236, Box 23)
    - Public Service Committee Hearings, December 12, 1989 (Folder 237, Box 23)
    - Public Service Committee Hearings, November 1990-Sept. 1991 (Folder 238, Box 23)
    - Public Service Committee Hearings, October 24, 1990 (Folder 239, Box 23)
    - Prepared Testimony of John. J. Mavretich (Folder 240, Box 23)
    - Informational Packets and Pamphlets (Folder 241, Box 23)
    - Misc. Newspaper Clippings (Folder 242, Box 23)
    - Recommended Decision by the Administrative Law Judges Thomas Redmond Matias and Walter T. Moynihan, Iroquois Gas Transmission System (Folder 243, Box 23)
    - Opinion No. 89-42, Iroquois as Transmission System (Folder 244, Box 23)
  - Subseries 1.10: Legislative Acts, 1.10; 0.33 linear feet Box: 24 Folders: 245 - 251
    Series contains various legislative acts researched and/or supported by Hudson Valley GREEN.
    Alphabetically and by Subjec
    - Bottle Bill (Folder 245, Box 24)
    - Environmental Bond Act (Folder 246, Box 24)
    - Environmental Quality Act (Folder 247, Box 24)
    - Johnson Wallop Bill (Folder 248, Box 24)
    - NYEQ Bond Act (Folder 249, Box 24)
    - Price Anderson Act (Folder 250, Box 24)
    - WRAP Act (Folder 251, Box 24)
  - Subseries 1.11: Nuclear Power Plants, 1.11; 0.33 linear feet Box: 25 Folders: 252 - 265
    Series contains Information collected by Hudson Valley GREEN on nuclear power plants including Indian Point, Nine Mile Island, Chernobyl and Shoreham.
    - Decommissioning (Folder 252, Box 25)
    - Nine Mile Island III (Folder 253, Box 25)
    - Nine Mile Island, comments by Charles Komanoff (Folder 254, Box 25)
    - Public Service Commission, News Releases on Nine Mile (Folder 255, Box 25)
    - New York Public Interest Research Group (Folder 256, Box 25)
    - Indian Point, Newspapers and clippings (Folder 257, Box 25)
    - Indian Point, Correspondence (Folder 258, Box 25)
    - Indian Point, General Information (Folder 259, Box 25)
    - Chernobyl, News releases and correspondence (Folder 260, Box 25)
    - Chernobyl, Printed Material (Folder 261, Box 25)
    - West Valley (Folder 262, Box 25)
    - Shoreham (Folder 263, Box 25)
    - Shoreham, Newspaper clippings (Folder 264, Box 25)
    - Summary of Application for State and Federal Permits to build an Electric Generating Station at New Haven or Stuyvesant (Folder 265, Box 25)
  - Subseries 1.12: Nuclear Energy, 1981 - 2002; 1.12; 0.67 linear feet Boxes: 26 - 27 Folders: 266 - 275
    Series contains Pamphlets and newspaper clippings collected by Hudson Valley GREEN on the implications of nuclear power, information collected on alternative power sources, Information on hydroelectric power, solar power, and the use of wood and wind as alternative energies.
    - Nuclear Power, Information Pamphlets (Folder 266, Box 26)
    - Nuclear Waste Repository (Folder 267, Box 26)
    - Medical Implications of Nuclear Power (Folder 268, Box 26)
    - Nuclear Waste Transportation (Folder 269, Box 26)
    - Nuclear Safety, Newspaper Clippings (Folder 270, Box 26)
    - Low Level Nuclear Waste, Newspaper Clippings (Folder 271, Box 26)
    - Nuclear Free Zones (Folder 272, Box 27)
    - Nuclear Weapon Freeze (Folder 273, Box 27)
    - Nuclear Weapons and Nuclear War (Folder 274, Box 27)
    - Nuclear Test Ban (Folder 275, Box 27)
  - Subseries 1.13: Power Sources / Renewable Energy, 1.13; 0.67 linear feet Box: 28 Folders: 276 - 294
    Series contains information collected by Hudson Valley GREEN on various alternative energy sources including wind, wood, and hydroelectric power.
    - Alternative / Appropriate Technologies (Folder 276, Box 28)
    - Coal (Folder 277, Box 28)
    - Coal Conversion (Folder 278, Box 28)
    - Electric Cars (Folder 279, Box 28)
    - Gasohol (Folder 280, Box 28)
    - Hydroelectric Power in New York (Folder 281, Box 28)
    - Joseph Newman Machine (Folder 282, Box 28)
    - Local Solar Power (Folder 283, Box 28)
    - Natural Gas (Folder 284, Box 28)
    - Ocean Thermal Power (Folder 285, Box 28)
    - New York State Energy (Folder 286, Box 28)
    - Quebec Hydroelectric (Folder 287, Box 29)
    - Quebec Hydro-connection (Folder 288, Box 29)
    - Renewable Energy (Folder 289, Box 29)
    - Solar Power, General Information (Folder 290, Box 29)
    - Solar Power, Political (Folder 291, Box 29)
    - Solar Powered Satellites (Folder 292, Box 29)
    - Wind (Folder 293, Box 29)
    - Wood (Folder 294, Box 29)
  - Subseries 1.14: Prattsville, 1.14; Box: 30 Folders: 295 - 303
    Series contains General information, correspondence, and clippings pertaining to the Prattsville issue
    Subject
    - Prattsville, General Information (Folder 295, Box 30)
    - Prattsville News Items (Folder 296, Box 30)
    - Correspondence with Congress (Folder 297, Box 30)
    - Misc. Handwritten Correspondence (Folder 298, Box 30)
    - Misc. Typed Correspondence (Folder 299, Box 30)
    - Newspaper clippings (Folder 300, Box 30)
    - New York State Energy Office, Correspondence and Testimony (Folder 301, Box 30)
    - Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, Correspondence (Folder 302, Box 30)
    - Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, Briefs (Folder 303, Box 30)
  - Subseries 1.15: Public Service Commission, Misc. Sessions, 1.15; Box: 31 Folders: 304 - 310
    Series contains Miscellaneous Public Service Commission Session Transcripts
    Chronological
    - Session, June 7, 1982 (Folder 304, Box 31)
    - Session, May 3&11, 1983 (Folder 305, Box 31)
    - Session, April 9, 1986 (Folder 306, Box 31)
    - Session, April 17, 1991 (Folder 307, Box 31)
    - Session, April 20, 1992 (Folder 308, Box 31)